"Quit part-time job"
Thanks for your support so far.
"Sell belongings"
We can pay for 30,000 yen in total.
"Bank"
I'll be withdrawing everything.
"I'll pay back your money"
"The last day"
Based on the manga
"Koe no Katachi " by Yoshitoki Oima
(Elementary school grade 6 class 2)
Director: Naoko Yamada
Hey, everyone sit down!
We have a new student today.
What is it?
You're lucky! It's a girl.
I'm not interested at all.
Well,
Then please introduce yourself.
Huh?
Oh...
"For written communication"
"Nice to meet you.  I am Shoko Nishimiya."
"I want to be friends with
you all via this notebook."
"Please use this notebook
when you talk to me."
"I can't hear."
Unbelievable...
Weird!
"Hi, Nishimiya-san. I am Miki Kawai."
Hi, nice to meet you.
Hey, Nishimiya-san, can you speak Japanese?
Nao-chan, how you say...
"Once again please."
Aha...
Huh?
Ok.
What did your friends call you?
Give up, give up!
I see, "Sho-chan".
Huh?
That's same as Ishida.
She is called Sho-chan, too.
That's so funny.
What?  That's not funny at all!
Please write down what I'm saying.
From pages 20 to page 25,
and drills on page 32.
That's what will be covered in the next test.
Hey.
Give me your notebook.
First, "fulcrum". The point
that supports the strength.
Next, "the effort point",
the point the strength is taken.
The point that has the weight
is the point of loading.
With these three points,
Nishimiya-san,
You are going too fast.
I will
teach you the timing, ok?
Then, let's start again from the beginning.
How shall we do in the
coming chorus competition?
We just already lost, didn't we?
That's the penalty for saying weird things!
Ouch, ouch!
Ouch!
So today
I missed what the teacher
said again because of her...
I'll lend you my notebook.
Thank you.
I am not wrong.
That's why I will never say sorry.
What a poor reading, Ueno.
Oh...
Crap. That's enough. Next!
The hell, ugly glasses.
Nishimiya.
From this sentence.
Ztop do be zdabborn aboud zach zings.
Mom zayz dizgazdingly,
bud I ave no indenzon do zay zorry.
Ok. Good. Next, Ishida.
Really? Unbelievable.
Hey, Ishida!  Stop that!
Ha ha ha...
Please let me know what
you are talking about.
Let's go home.
Bye-bye, Nishimiya-san.
Hey you,
Aren't you going to frustrate your classmates?
What?
SL: I,
SL: And you,
SL: Friends?
frie-nds...
What?
Disgusting!
I'm Kita, I'm in a special education class.
Today I wanna talk about "Shuwa" or sign language.
Write as "speaking with hands" and pronounce "Shu-wa".
As the word says, Shuwa means speaking using your hands.
Isn't it amazing?
Sign...language...
So I am proposing a three-minute lesson
of sign language everyday morning,
to understand Shoko-chan even more.
Teacher.
Yes?
Isn't it enough to use her notebook?
It's easier for Shoko-chan using sign language.
It's easier for me using the notebook.
I'll learn sign language.
"Teach me sign language for Sahara Miyoko"
Sa - ara
I - jo - ko
Got it!
Sa - a ...
Good job getting brownie points.
I love him so much.  He is so handsome.
Agreed!
He will be in the drama next
week. You must see it!
Don't you think her clothes are ugly?
Stop it, Nao-chan.
The author described through this work...
After the experiment,
manganese dioxide should be...
Hirose, you write that side.
Ni-shi-mi-ya.
What are you doing, Ishida ?
Isn't better to stop that?
Star.
Ishida, you are going too far.
No, no, that's how it should be.
You're a bad guy.
Nice, nice.
It's really nice.
That's so bad! Who did such nasty things!
Too bad!
I... will... kindly...
erase... it... for... you...
Ok.
All erased.
Thank you.
You are welcome.
Let's go.
Joumon-era was...
Hey, Ishida.
Class is not over.
I see. I'm sorry.
Well...I forgot what I was talking about...
Well, what kind of house
were they living? They lived..
Are you so surprised?
Hey, Nishimiya-san.
Does this mean you can actually hear?
Yeah, I thought the same thing, too.
Please let me see it for a while?
Ueno.
What is it?  Gimme.
Oh, what is this?
It's filthy!
Ouch!
Wh--What?
Oh my god,
Nishimiya-san, are you ok?
What should I do....?
Nishimiya-san.
Hey, you went too far.
Crap, so annoying, ugly glasses.
What? Go away.
Don't interrupt.
What is she doing?
Let's go home.
"I'm sorry."
You liar!
If you want to say something to me, say it!
What!?
Stop it, you are disgusting!
Oh, Nishimiya-san is funny!
Shoya, you are blushing, aren't you?
No, I'm not!
SL: I,
SL: And you,
SL: Friends?
Let's go.
Huh?
Oh, is she serious, Nishimiya-san?
It's unbelievable!
See you tomorrow, Shoya.
Well, today I have a topic I
want to talk about to you all.
It's about Nishimiya-san,
who is absent today.
Yesterday we had a call from
Nishimiya-san's mother.
She said eight of Nishimiya-san's
hearing aids have gone missing
or been damaged in the past five months.
Nishimiya-san's mother is worried
that she is being bullied at school.
If any of you know anything
about any bullying
or similar harassment addressed to
Nishimiya-san, please let us know.
We hear her hearing aids are very expensive.
So please confess, before your
parents get in trouble.
Hey, Ishida.
We all know it was you.
Stand up right now!
Yes.
Ueno.
What do you think, sitting next to him?
Well...so...
He might be doing something to prank her?
What?
How about you, Shimada?
I'd been saying
"Hey, stop it" to him,
but Shoya wouldn't stop.
What!?
Hey, Shimada,
You did it with me together, didn't you?
And, the girls said terrible
things about her so many times.
Hey!
Especially Ueno and Kawai.
What!?
How cruel you all are..
I never did such things.
Why are you telling such lies?
Ishida-kun, you were bad too.
He made her cry.
Huh?  Why is this here...?
I see.  Yes.
I'm very sorry.
I see.  I see.
Thank you for calling.
Shoya.
Stop now, Shoya!
I got a call from school.
You...
Why are you so wet?
Shut up! I jumped in the river like always.
Wait, Shoya.
Did you cause trouble to someone?
I don't know.
Is what your teacher said correct?
Y...Yes!
Prepare to go out right now.
We have to meet Nishimiya-san's.
(Mizuho Bank)
Sho-chan, let's go home.
Be a good boy from tomorrow, ok?
Huh?  It's missing...
Great men and women experienced hard times, and...
Huh?
What?
What is she doing?
Hey, what are you doing with my desk?
What were you doing?  Disgusting!
Same smile again.
Don't pretend to be a good girl!
What?
If you wanna say something to me, say it now!
You are always showing that disgusting smile.
You are angry, aren't you!?
Hey!
Say something!
Ouch!
What you are doing!
What do you mean!
Doigg mah bezd...
I'b doigg mah bezd!
What are you saying!
What!
I cannot understand
what you are saying!
"Disappear"
Crap...
She is so disgusting...
Nishimiya-san has transferred to another school.
Huh.
Hey, the class journal was not submitted today.
Who is in charge?
And, who is in charge of keeping the flowers?
"Sign Language Study Club"
SL : Hello.
Hi, Shoko-chan.  Hello.
Nishimiya!
Do you remember me?
I was your classmate in elementary school...
Shoya Ishida.
Nishimiya?
Wait!
Nishimiya!
Where?
Nishimiya.
H...Hi.
Well...
Here it is.
I came here to give this to you.
This is what you left behind.
SL: Why you know sign language?
You're asking "why sign language?"
I learned it.
So, here. ...
You might not want to see this again.
Well...
I...and...
Nishimiya,
Can we be...
friends?
Damn, what am I saying!?
H...hey, you said so in the past.
I finally understood what you said...
Oh...Please don't cry.
Please don't cry, Nishimiya.
Can I be friends with you?
Sho-tan,
Sho-tan, wake up!
Breakfast!
Sho-chan, wake up!
Good morning, Maria.
Sho-tan woke up!
I'm leaving.
Bye bye, Mom!
Here, Sho-chan.
Let's eat.
Dig in!
Huh?
Why you are smiling?
Because of...
this!
Oh.
You worked hard,
and you sold everything, even including beddings.
I'm very happy for all of your efforts.
By the way, Sho-chan...
Why did you try to kill yourself?
Yeah, actually,
It's a long story you know,
But it's because...
I knew it...
Huh!?
I knew it!
I knew something was going on with you!
Your room was extraordinarily empty,
your phone was out of service,
and the calendar...
Pages after April were torn off...
Right now promise you will never try to
kill yourself, or I'll burn this.
For earning the 1,700,000 yen
you worked so hard for!
Hey, are you listening to me!?
Huh!?
Don't be stupid, mom...
YOU ARE stupid, what an
ungrateful child you are!
Hey, well, ah...
Sorry.
I'm really sorry.
I'll stop.
I'll stop.  I'm sorry.
You'll stop what, say it clearly!
I'll stop trying to kill myself!
Really?
Really!
Ok, that's a promise.
Hey! Mom!
Ouch!
Hey, water, water!
Yesterday, I thought about
killing myself by jumping into a
river from some very high bridge.
The reason I went to meet Nishimiya
was also like a ceremony before it.
It was the biggest challenge of my life
but the story has changed...
"Friend"
Stupid!  Why did I say such a thing!?
When just entered junior high school, Shimada said,
You'd better stay away from a guy named Shoya Ishida.
He is...
a bully.
What I did had all come
back to haunt me.
I fully realized
that I had to take responsibility
of what I had did.
And I was isolated.
Good morning.
Then
Translate these sentences by the next lesson.
Ishida-kun.
H-hi.
Kawai...
Can I gather your math
homework if you finished it?
Oh...sorry, I have forgotten it.
Ok, I see.
Please finish it soon as
the deadline is coming up.
Yes, I will.  Sorry.
Let's have lunch outside.
"Ishida-kun is always alone as you can see."
"Everyone knows it."
Oh, really?
"Oh, he is looking at us as always."
"Isn't he feeling desolate,
always being alone?"
"He will always be the same."
"Why is he still living?"
H...Hi, here it is.
I just bought this limited edition, and...
Oops.
Then I'll quit being a fan of them.
Me too.
That's the reality...
Huh?
I remember that hair.
Who is he?
By the way,
can I meet Nishimiya again?
She said she feeds the carp in the river.
Do you have a reason?
Can I see her to apologize what I did?
She said she will be there every Tuesday.
Would it be weird if I see her again?
I'm home.
Sho---chan?
Whoops,
I'm so surprised.
What?
I'm very sorry for what happened this morning.
I burned the money you worked so hard for.
But I didn't want to use any of the money
that you saved to die.
Sorry, I'll save up again.
Thanks.
You can take your time, ok?
You are hungry, huh?  Let's have dinner.
Hungry!
Tuesday.
Hey you, why don't you lend your bike to me?
Me?
Oh, the guy I remember.
I left something behind.  I want to go home to get it.
Huh?  What are you saying?
You should use your own.
I asked you 'cause I don't have my own.
Stop it please.
Hey, don't resist.
Oops. Stop it!
Someone please help me!
Someone!
Oh, dear.
Please, please help me!  Help!  Help!
Shut up!
Stop resisting!
H...hey.
I...I'll lend you mine.
Really!?  You are super!
It was ripped off.
Actually, today of all days is Tuesday.
This means I should not see her again?
Of course I still can go by foot,
but it seems as I was told not to go.
Reason.
Something very smart,
and natural reason to see her again.
A discount coupon for just-baked tasty bread?
That's it!
Well...Is Nishimiya-san here?
No, she isn't
She is, isn't she?
Shoko Nishimiya isn't here.
Sorry but,
are you really a friend of Shoko?
Bye.
Nothing.
I found a rat.
A big creepy one.
Don't be afraid.  It won't come again.
Friend...
Huh?
Why...is he here?
O--Oh, he is!
Ishida-kun!
Look! Look!
A bike!  It's yours, isn't it?
Good timing!
Huh, you were lucky that your
address was written on the bike.
Wh...where was the bike?
It was abandoned in a rice paddy!
I was looking all over for this!
I'm glad I got it back to you!
Is something wrong, Ishida-kun?
H-hey
Well..
Your name?
Oops!  I'm Nagatsuka!
I sit just behind you in the class.
Oh, I see.
Won't you eat some bread?
This is so good, Nagatsuka-kun.
Ishida-kun.
Ishida-kun!
Good morning!
H..Hi, good morning!
Ishida-kun!
Why don't we hang out after school?
As we are now friends.
Ishida-kun, come here, come here!
What's wrong with you, Ya-sho?
Well.
Nothing.
Ya... "Ya-sho"?
Sounds like a "big friend", doesn't it?
Anyway, what are you worrying about?
You can tell me anything,
cause we are true friends.
Nagatsuka-kun.
What is the definition of "friend"?
A kind of license,
or right or something like that,
to become friends with someone.
Hey, Ya-sho.
Give me your hand.
Hey, hey.
This is friendship.
I think, Ishida-kun,
friendship exists beyond such words and logic.
License? No such things are needed.
It's a ridiculous idea.
She is not here.
She is, isn't she?
She isn't!
Huh, who are you anyway?
I'm Shoko's boyfriend.
Oops!... Dropped.
Ha ha, that not about me, but a bread.
O...oh, really?
Nishimiya likes younger guys.
I'm a little surprised by that.
Ok, at least give this bread to her?
This is very good bread.
Hey.
Don't come here again,
if you only want to satisfy yourself.
Are you satisfied?
Then bye.
Hey boy!
My friend wants to see Nishimiya-san!
Stop complaining and bring her here right now!
Nagatsuka-kun, why are you here?
I followed you.
Sounds like a behavior of best friends?
Haha, so the friend of a turd had a turd hair.
Hey, you a turd-hair!
Wh---what are you saying?!
Say that again boy!
Turd-hair, turd-hair, turd-hair!
What's happening?
Is that Yuzuru-chan?
Oh, no.  They are fighting.
You, small boy!
Nagatsuka-kun
Stop it, ok?
This is enough, so let's go home.
Nagatsuka-ku...
Oh?  Aren't you the boy from the other day?
I--it's not like that!
Nagatsuka-kun, sorry for leaving you!
Crap!
Crap, she found and met him.
Good for you, Ishida-kun!
Hey boy.
You are peeping now, aren't you?
Let me use it now!
What?
SL: Long time no see.
Ishida-kun is waving his hands and doing something!?
It's sign language.
SL: Have you been well?
Really!?
Wow, I didn't know he knew that.
Hey, you can read their sign language.
Then translate it for me!
Who was that turd-hair just now?
SL: I'm glad to see you again.
SL: Are you ok leaving your sign language class?
I don't know such turd.
Oops, he was so creepy!
S-T-O-P J-O-K-I-N-G!
Leave me alone!
Tsk!
Be careful not to fall, boy.
"Honestly,"
"I was not sure if it was
ok for me to see you again."
"A kind of license to be friends with you"
"I have been looking you in the past two weeks."
"Reason to"
"See you again"
"I have been looking for it."
Ishida-kun...
Huh?
"I'm glad."
"I thought"
"the same thing as you."
"That is so strange."
Well..
Nishimiya, here it is. A bread,
To feed the carp.
Feeding is fun?
Oh, I was just reminded.
Huh?
SL: Thank you.
Well...
Nishimiya...
Y..you had better not read it
so much!
Hey!  wait, Nishimiya!
Oh!  She fell!
What!?  Something happened to Ishida-kun!?
Hey!
Hey, boy!
Oops!  Ishida-kun fell to the river!
Why!?
Ouch!
Why did you do it!
Oops, what is this creepy thing!?
Nishimiya.
Nishimiya!
Sorry for dropping the notebook.
See you.
SL: See you again.
Shoko, you are so stupid...
Ha ha..
Stupid!
Did you see this?
Hey, isn't this guy Ishida-kun?
"See you again"
Can I?
Hey.
This is Ishida-kun, isn't it?
This guy.
What?
What's this.
Ishida-kun, come to the
teachers' room right now.
"Notice of short-term suspension
from school - Shoya Ishida"
"I am very sorry that I jumped
into Suimon River from a bridge,
where it was prohibited to do so, and..
I also uploaded that photo to the web.. "
Hey, Shoya.
What?
Sorry but could you pick
Maria back from the nursery?
I'm suspended from school and prohibited to go out.
It would be ok if you could
do it quickly.  Please!!
H..hey!!
Maria, let's go home now!
Sho-tan!
Someone is in there!
Ouch!
Hey.
Hey, are you ok?
Aren't you Nishimiya's boyfriend?
You'll catch a cold.
Huh?  Oh, the rat.
What are you doing here?
Shoes?
...Why don't you get angry with me?
What?
I am the person who uploaded the photo.
Oh, you did it.
I did it.
I am relieved to hear that.
Why?
I want to know the reason why.
Get mad at me.
I cannot.
Blame me.
Sho-tan!
I am hungry!
Ok!
Then I'll go home.
You go home, too.
Ha ha, you have a kid.
Ouch!
It's not mine, my sis's.
Hey!
Hi Yuzuru-chan,
Please eat enough!
How about sis?
She'll is working late today.
Maria, isn't it too hot?
No, it's good!
Yuzuru-kun, why don't you eat?
Hi, Yuzuru-kun!
Please!
SL: You should apologize,
SL: Or I don't need you!
Crap...
Huh?
What's the matter with you.
I was worried when you
disappeared in the night.
Here! Umbrella.
O--oh!
Anyway, use it!
Well, please use it now.
Thank you.
Well, excuse me.
I knew that.
I'll give you these.
This was mine, but
I don't use them anymore.
I'll give them to you.
Why did you run away from home?
I had an argument with Shoko.
Oh..
That's a kind of typical
for long-lasting couples, isn't it?
Yes.
like when I used Shoko's shampoo
without her permission.
I see...
I was told she doesn't need me.
Hey, are you living together with her!?
Use your umbrella.
You have only one, don't you?
I am to be blamed as I brought
only one umbrella.
I don't want Nishimiya's
boyfriend get wet and sick.
Hey you.
What kind of a man you intend
to be?  A hypocrite?
What!?
You like taking care of a poor stray cat?
Or do you make fun when doing it.
And you also made fun of her
hearing disability, I know.
Hey.
Then, now you learned sign language huh?
What's this?
Do you think you have changed
into a good person?
You are disgusting.
I see.
It's natural you know what I did,
hearing from Nishimiya.
Yes.  You are right.
I'm the worst human being.
I'm the one who doesn't deserve living.
But, at least,
I thought I don't want Nishimiya to cry again.
Of course, I have no intention
to interfere with the two of you.
No intention. Ever.
But, actually,
It's an issue of myself, too...
Thanks, it's enough here.
Ok.
Well..
I'm very sorry that you believed what I said..
But actually I'm Shoko's...
You understand?
Oops!
You are her little sis!?
Bye!
Oh, Nishimiya-san's mother...
Hey, let's go.
Hey, it hurts.
I'm very sorry...
I'm home.
Yu-ju,
Hey, sis!
I'b zorry, I'b zorry!
All right, no problem.
Hey.
I wanna drink gramma's beefsteak plant juice.
Yuzuru.
Don't be friends with such a guy.
Say same thing to Shoko from you, too.
We can decide such a thing by ourselves.
Both I and sis.
Hey boy!
Nice to see you!
Why are you here today?
To return his umbrella I borrowed the other day.
Oh boy.
You are doing a good thing.
Nagatsuka-kun, she is not a boy...
Little sis of Nishimiya.
Of course, I knew it.
I'm glad to see a friend of
my best friend Ya-sho.
He is my classmate,
Na-ga-tsu-ka.
Hey, hey!
Well..
I got my new smartphone.
Do you have a smartphone too?
Then you enjoy texting?
To whom?
Your classmates?
Oh, that's good.
Then do you have someone
you want to add to text to?
The address of someone you want to know.
Great, then my address is...
What?
Sa...Ha...Ra.
Sahara-san?  The classmate
from elementary school?
Ya-sho, Ya-sho!
Then?
Are you going to look for Sahara-san?
Don't joke.  I'm not such a girl.
But I really think Kawai-san is very clever.
Kawai-san...
Ya-sho?
But Mashiba-kun is also..
Kawai-san...?
What?
I..I have
something to ask of you.
Do you know the phone number
or something to contact
Sahara-san, our classmate
in elementary school?
Sahara-san?
Sorry, I don't know,
But I know her school,
as she belongs the same high school as Nao-chan.
Taiyo Girl's High School...
Shoot! I don't have enough money.
Ishida-kun.
Use this.
What!?  I don't need that much!
Don't mind, Ya-sho.
When you need travel, meal,
and then love hotel expenses,
You will be need that much.
Hey!
We are here!
My sis says
She's pissed at you since you are looking
for a past classmate without her.
So take her with you, Ishida.
Are you tired?
Thank you for today.
I am happy to hear that you are
trying to look for Sahara-san.
I have heard some news about you from Yuzuru.
I'm happy being together today!
Well...
Walking from here..
Sho-chan?
Sorry.
Sho-chan!
I'm Sahara!
Do you remember me?
Hello!
Huh?  Ishida-kun?
Heh heh heh.
Long time no see.
I continued to study sign language after that.
Is this correct?
When you disappeared in elementary school
I'm sorry.
I have been thinking of Sho-chan for long time.
I'm happy to see you again.
And surprised.
SL: Me too.
Hum, hum...
Oh, really?
Huh, and now,
What kind of school you are going to?
I see.
And, hey, your chest got big, you know.
What's your cup size?
I'll check for myself!
Where are you going?
A restroom.
I see.
Hello!  We are handing out
discount coupons for you!
Discount coupon!
Ueno..
Here it is.
Meow Meow Club...
From: Sahara-san
It's great you learned sign language.
And thank you for bringing us together!
Oh!
Sahara is so aggressive.
I cannot behave like her...
Hmm?
Can I bring Ueno together, too?
Huh?  That's impossible, you know?
Yeah, I know, I know.
I think so, too.
Yes.
Let's go, Nagatsuka-kun.
Now is the time to go
to the "Meow Meow Club"!
Can I help you?
How long are you going to stay?
One hour, please.
Can we use this coupon?
Yes, you can.
Oh, unbelievable.  He actually came...
Well, what should I say, but...
What did you expect?
So did you.
No no.  Don't be stupid.
I was simply interested
in your old friend.
Yes, your friend.
Is she here?
Actually, she's not a friend.
Then what?
It's a little complicated.
Something happened during elementary school.
She doesn't seem to be here today.
Let's go home then.
Oh, really..
Insect!
Hi, you came here.
Came to play with Maria.
By the way, will Nishimiya be
pleased if I gave this pouch?
Huh?
A cat!
Sis, I've got something for you!
...Sis?
I'll put the present for you here.
What?
U--Ueno..
-san?
Go, go!
Wait, wait, what is it!?
Long time no see!
Yeah.  Long time no see.
Huh?
The girl over there is Nishimiya, isn't she?
She seems still alone, ha ha.
So sad!
Ishida!  It's been really a
long time since seeing you.
Let's hang out together shortly.
No thank you.
Ishida, you hate me, don't you?
I don't know.
Actually,
I have been thinking
I should have talked to you earlier.
I'm sorry when we were
in elementary school.
Ueno, get off my bike.
Why does she have the pouch of the
cat cafe I'm working in?
Why? So weird!
I gave it to her.
Oh...I see.
Good-bye.
Bye.
Ueno?
Nishimiya-san, long time no see!
Are you all right?
H..hey!!
Huh?  Why do you wear only one?
Ueno!  What are you doing!?
Throwing it away to play,
like we did in the past.
Sorry, Nishimiya.
Are you joking, Ishida?
Wait! Wait a moment!
Are you two going out together?
No, nothing like that.
Just friends.
Friends?
Don't make me laugh!
You are friends with the girl you bullied?
Why?
I don't follow you!
Oh, I understand.
A kind of sense of guilt?
No.
Ha ha.
Ishida, you have became such a boring guy.
Now you two are playing friends!
Ha ha ha.
Huh?
SL: What did you talk about?
"What were you two talking about"?
N--Nothing special.
Well, I have to go now.
See you again.
Yuju,
I'z mornigg.
I'm quite awake.  So surprised.
Bregbazt, lez eed now.
Wait, wait, before that..
What's happened?
Sis.
Ponytail today?  Why?
Oh.
What a weird face!
Then make Ishida have a chance to see her!
So many carp.  Feeding manpower and bread shorted.
You MUST come.
Huh?
Nishimiya..
Ponytail!?
Whea are yu goig, Ijida-gun?
"Where are you going?"
I'm going to a bread shop.
Yuzuru asked to buy a bread for feeding carp.
Yuju muzt habe id.  Yuju only
wand do ead bi herzelb.
Hey, Nishimiya!
Ijida-gun, don'd need do go
Wait, wait.  Sign language!  Sign language!
Iz mai voize stranze?
Yes.
Oh, sorry.
Oh...
it's completely ok.
W--well, I have to go now. Bread.
Then bye.
Oh?
Nishimiya?
Huh? You giving me this?
Thanks.
Can I open it here?
...What are these?
...Thank you very much.
...ige...oo...
What?
About this?
I...ige...moo...
Huh?...
I lige moo!
Moon?
Agree.
It's beautiful.
Ni..Nishimiya!?
(From: Big friend Nagatsuka)
How about we go out and see a movie now?
Hey Nagatsuka-kun,
Can you see this as a moon?
Huh?  I cannot see this as a moon.
Hummm.
C--Candy?
It is not candies.
Nishimiya gave them just now,
but I'm not sure what these are.
Huh?
Oh..
What's the matter, sis?
"I said I like you to Ishida-kun"
Oh, really!?
But he didn't understand what I said.
Huh...
Wow, you have changed your hairstyle.
Why changed?  What happened?
It matches you so much!
Stop, stop you all.
I was in a bit of rush this morning, that's all.
But that looks great anyway.
Hi, Kawai-san.
Why you have changed your hairstyle?
Hummm.
I don't have any special reason to do it.
I see.
That's what girls do, you know?
Ok.
What?
By the way, Mashiba-kun
said he wants to be friends with you.
Huh?
Why...why are you here today.
I'm Sahara, nice to meet you.
Me too.  I'm Mashiba.
Hey!  Stop doing that over my head!
Miyo-chan, long time no see.
By the way, where is Nishimiya today?
Sis went home as she had a stomachache.
Umm..
I wonder if she is avoiding me...?
Why do you think so?
The other day,
She was trying hard to tell me something,
but I couldn't understand what she said.
Huh, what did sis tried to tell?
Moon
Pff!
I can't understand very simple words she said.
I guess that would make her mad.
If you want to know if
sis is avoiding you or not,
why don't you invite
her out for something?
If she is angry, she will say "no".
Oh,
That's a good idea.
(From: Ishida)  We plan to go to an amusement park,
and how about going together if you like?
Hi all, let's start with that roller coaster!
Follow me so that you don't lost!
Hey, why is that girl leading us?
I don't know.
Ishida.
Who's that girl?
Oh!
She seems too familiar with sis.
Ueno.. Why..
Is she Shoko's friend?
Y--yes.
When we were in the elementary school.
Hmmmm...
Can I sit next to you, Sahara-san?
Yeah, of course.
Are you all ready?
Yeah!!
Then let's start.
Sahara-san are you ok to be with Ueno?
Huh?
Yes.
I'm in the same class
with her in high school.
I'm learning a lot of her
taste and skill for clothes.
I had been scared to ride this
when I was in the elementary school.
I was a coward at that time.
But I changed my ways a bit.
I decide to ride it before I
decide if it is scary or not.
Actually, I am still scared a bit.
Hey, it comes!
Hey, are you ok?
Your legs are so trembling, Sho-chan.
"Are you ok?"
Ha ha.
It's fantastic that you can use sign language!
You did your best to learn
sign language, Ishida-kun!
Huh?
SL: Fun!
Hey, is this hand yours?
You are so rude to my best friend Ya-sho!
Huh?  I simply want to be friends with him.
No, don't act like a child!
Nagatsuka-kun is so funny!
My permission is needed
when you speak to Ya-sho!
Nagatsuka-kun, is your hair natural one?
What!?  Don't be silly!
Hey! Stop touching my hair!
Wait..
Mashiba-kun, go faster!
Go, go, Ya-sho, go!
Wait..
Can I...?
Can I enjoy it like this?
But it seems like that..
Oops!
What are you doing?!
It seems like..
Friends!
Ishida.
I want to eat "takoyaki" ball snacks.
Let go and buy it together.
What!? Hey!
Here's takoyaki.  Thank you for buying.
Thank you very much.
Hey you, Ueno,
I don't want unnecessary kindness.
Shi...Shimada...
Hey!
Hey, Ishida!
Oh!
Sorry, but I'll text you later.
Ishida!
Are you angry?
No. I'm not angry.
Angry -- No.
I just thought
if you two meet again,
you could be friends again.
Things might go well if you two met again.
Don't do such misplaced kindness.
Oops.
I did the same things to them...
You and me are alike, huh?
No. we are not.
We are alike.
We are not.
Well.
If Nishimiya-san hadn't come,
we all would have been happy.
Don't jump to such conclusions.
But wasn't I correct?
If she had not been there,
I would not have a quarrel with Sahara,
and the friendship between Ishida and
Shimada would have not been broken.
I want to go back to the
time when Nishimiya-san came.
As for things with Shimada,
I simply did so intentionally.
Ishida, do you hate me?
Perhaps yes.
Now I feel like riding the ferris wheel.
Want to ride with Nishimiya-san.
H--hey!
Huh?
Nishimiya-san, let's ride a ferris whee together.
Hey, Ueno!
Sis, sorry but take this camera with you.
I'm going to ride the jet coaster again.
Hi, you are welcome, Yuzuru-chan.
Shoya is in his room.
Hi.
I got a highly confidential movie.
Movie in the ferris wheel?
Yes.
Huh?  What do you mean?
Peeping cam.
Well, I...
I hate you.
Let's not use it.
I'll speak clearly so that
you can understand
and I'll listen what you say.
In elementary school days,
I didn't understand you enough.
But, I think you didn't
understand us, too.
That's why it bothered me
with your weird notebook
and always smiled insincerely.
You always said sorry
when something happened.
So I changed my feelings.
I ignored you and talked
about you behind your back.
Those were my messages,
not to bother us any more.
But,
you didn't understand and got us back.
By ratting on us to the adults.
As a result, Ishida lost his friends,
Lot of things around us
were broken because of you.
I...I'b zorry...
Actually, I don't want you to apologize.
Our view was very narrow
minded during childhood,
and we did our best
within that limitations.
But I don't wanna tell you
let's be friends now.
I still hate you, and
You still hate me.
But how about declaring
peace between you and me?
So let's shake hands, even
though we both hate each other.
Zat'z nod gorregd...
I hade myzelf...
So what?
What's that?
Then?
You say "I'm sorry" again!?
After all,
you are shutting your mind to talk
with me, as you did five years ago.
What do you think?
I want Nishimiya
to like Nishimiya herself.
Ueno--san, right?
Yes. Ueno?
Did Nishimiya-san have trouble with her?
Why do you think so?
Kawai-san said there was
something in elementary school.
By the way, I was surprised
Nishimiya-san was really unable to hear.
Yes, she is.
Oh, then, I guess,
she was bullied because of that?
I cannot forgive
that kind of bully,
How do you think, Ishida-kun?
What do you mean!?
You say I am spreading what
you did in the past!?
Hey, you talk too loud...
After all, Ishida-kun has not
changed at all from the past!
What!?
You have always told me cruel
things since elementary school!
What's the matter, Ya-sho?
Calm down, Kawai-san.
What are you talking about?
Mashiba-kun!
Ishida-kun used to bully
a girl in the past.
What are you saying, Kawai-san?
Don't be silly..
It is true.
Kawai-san also said
bad things at that time...
I never said bad words
to Nishimiya-san!
What!? Nishimiya-san!?
Yes.
Ishida-kun bullied Nishimiya-san.
I asked him please
to stop doing that,
but he never listened
to what I said.
He scared me so much..
Ya-sho?
Oops...
Are you ok?
Sorry, Nagatsuka-kun..
Ya-sho..
Ya-sho!
I hate myself, too...
Hi, Ishida.
Hi!
What's wrong?
SL : Are you all right?
No, nothing special.
Nothing..
Huh?
Hey, Ishida-kun, you are here!
I'm bringing your bag here!
Hey.
Nao-chan..
...I asked her to come.
I'm sorry what happened in
the classroom, Ishida-kun.
But,
originally you are to blame, I think.
SL: What's going on?
if Ishida-kun apologizes first,
we can forgive him,
Mashiba-kun said so, and..
Stop it.
That's not the proper way.
We have no right to blame
him in this matter.
"We"?
That's not correct, Nao-chan.
What's not?
Different from me,
Nao-chan actually bullied
Nishimiya-san too.
You should not treat me like yourself.
Nao-chan..
Hummm.
You're right.  We are different.
Completely different from you.
You were just looking on and
laughed at her being bullied.
Too bad!
Hey, Sahara, how do you think about this?
Me!?
Nao-chan also said so many
bad things to Sahara-san.
I just said true things!
Hey, answer now, Sahara!
I..I was..
At that time..
I was scared of both of you.
What!?  Whose side are you on!?
I'm not on either side of you two!
Stop it.
It's all my fault.
I hate that kind of logic.
Stop, Ueno.
Don't conclude everything by yourself.
Ishida-kun, don't talk in such way...
Stop, Sahara.
You will run away like the past and regret,
"I was a coward".
What is wrong with you, Ishida-kun?
Stop speaking, Kawai.
You simply like yourself the most.
Ya-sho,
I'm always on your side...
Don't say such a thing without knowing me.
That's enough! I'm going home!
Ya-sho..
It's all right. I don't mind at all.
Sho-chan,
See you again.
Sorry, Ishida.
I regret coming here.
Ishida-kun, you were really bad.
Don't be in touch, you outsider.
I had thought we were friends.
Oh, by the way,
from next week,
summer holidays will start.
Why don't we go somewhere fun together?
Yuzu.
You'll hurt your eyes seeing
something in such a dark place.
Here.
Yuzu, are you still worried about sis?
Gramma worries about you, Yuzuru.
You always care about your sis,
and don't care about yourself.
You are doing the same thing, gramma?
You don't join senior people groups
and study sign language all the time.
That's just what I want to do.
Then so do I. I also do
what I'm doing for myself.
Really?
You are a very good granddaughter, Yuzu.
I don't think so.
I'm scolded everyday by mom,
and I have not gone to school for a while.
Yuzu have a very beautiful mind.
Shoko is also doing best everyday.
I'm very proud of having
very good granddaughters.
How about a sweet manju?
Yes, of course!
SL: I want to kill myself.
Grandma...
Hi Nishimiya.
Today I got very good bread.
This bread is
as wonderful as you,
so..
Hummm, does this sound strange?
Huh...?
Nishimiya didn't come today?
Well..
"Hi, Nishimiya, do you have
a stomachache today too?"
Hummm, this message is not good.
Hey, Yuzu...
I'll go home now...
Ishida.
Hey!
What are you wearing?
What?  This is my school uniform.
How you feel, how you feel?!
What?
About school.
But it is summer vacation now.
Uhh..
Actually, what's wrong with you?
Nothing.
If I say something.. Is it a kind of cosplay!?
Huh.
Text from my sis.  I have to go.
I'll take you.  Where?
No thank you.
I will.
Actually don't wanna you to.
You cried just now.
Why?
It's got nothing to do with you, Ishida.
Yes it does..
I want to think it does.
Why?
I worry about Yuzuru.
Don't say what my grandma says.
Then I don't care if you follow me.
Thank you Ishida.
It's enough here.
"Funeral site for Ito Nishimiya"
Bye.
Hold out, Yuzuru!
Ishida.
I found myself still scared a bit.
SL: Grandma...
SL : Yes, must be gramdma.
(To: Nishimiya) How about
hanging out somewhere tomorrow?
SL: It's refreshing.
Oh, it's splendid.
Com'on, Nishimiya.  Let's go far.
Huh?
Nishimiya?
Oops!
Haha.. I'm a bit scared.
SL: I'm sorry.
What?  Why did you say sorry now?
SL: You'll be unhappy as far as you are with me.
I Didn't say such a ridiculous thing!
Hey, Nishimiya, how about tomorrow?
Let's hang out tomorrow, too!
Ok?  Nishimiya.
Nishimiya said that
I will be unhappy as long
as I am together with her.
The person who made
Nishimiya unhappy
was me, actually..
I want to see the ocean,
I want to love a person,
even a monster has
a heart..
Sigh.
Cannot imagine how I can
recover a relationship...
Nishimiya!  Today Yuzuru is here, too!
Then let's go to see a movie!
SL: Hello.
Ha ha ha, how funny it is!
Hey, I'm here today!
What a fruitful summer holidays this year!
You agree on that, Yuzuru?
I don't know..
It's really full of happiness.
Hey, Nishimiya,
How about tomorrow?
Let's go out somewhere tomorrow, too!
We cannot go tomorrow, we have something to do.
What?
SL: Let's make it together.
Really!?  Are you serious!?
What are you going to do?
I---is that ok?
Is it ok for me to be here?
Now that Ishida is assigned to help us
to make a birthday cake for our mother.
Really?
I---is that ok?
Your mom will slap me again, won't she?
It might be even more than that.
She might even kill you.
Hey!
Oh, it looks delicious!
What?  Why is this guy here?
Shoko, what do you intend to do?
Get out now..
Stop, mother!  Today is your celebration day!
Yuzuru.
You look good with this!
Huh..
Tastes good!
It was good that you
didn't get killed, Ishida.
Y--Yes.
Good job, sis!
By the way, Yuzuru.
I submitted some of your photos
to the prefectural photo contest.
What?
Sho-chan wanted to submit them for you.
SL: Mom selected the photo.
But I suppose all the photos are kind of creepy.
Not necessarily so.
Hey, you two did it without asking me!
Pff..
By the way, there will be a
fireworks festival next Tuesday.
SL: Let's go together.
Humm, I'd like to pass.
Let's go together.
Is it ok here?  Yes, yes.
Well, I'll go to buy fried noodles.
Let's go together.
Oh thank you.
Well, thank you for inviting me
to your house the other day.
Your mom..
Yes, yes.
Did she enjoy the party?
Basically she had no facial expressions, but..
When is your birthday, Nishimiya?
June
7th.
Oh, it has already passed!
Well..
You are 18 years old already.
Next year, let's celebrate
your birthday together.
Oops,
I said "together" unintentionally.
Oh.
SL: I'm feeling it by the body, instead of ear.
I see.
Understood!
It's interesting.
Oh, what's up?
SL: I'll be going.
But fireworks are not over yet?
SL: To study.
"Study"..
I see.
Then I'll go with you.
SL: No, I'm ok.
But..
SL: I'm ok.
I see.
See you again.
SL: Thank you.
What?  what happened to sis?
Ishida,
can you go to our apartment
to pick up my camera?
Good evening..
Oh, it's dark.
Nishimiya, I'm here.
Here it is.
Is it charging ok..?
Huh?  oh, we can see the fireworks from here.
Found Nishimiya.
Hi, Nishimi..ya..
Nishimiya?
Wait, wait!  Wait a moment!
What are you doing?!
Nishimiya?
Nishimiya..!?
Huh!
Nishimiya!
Ouch!
Shoko!
Why..
Why, Nishimiya..
Nishimiya, railing!
Grab the railing!
Please, God..
Give me just one more ounce of strength.
I won't run from my
challenges im my life.
From tomorrow,
I'll look at everyone's face.
I'll listen to everyone's voice from tomorrow.
I'll do everything properly from tomorrow...
Ni..Nishimiya..
Oh, the scar I made at that time...
Did I properly apologize for that?
Sorry.
Sorry, Nishimiya.
Are you still mad?
Crap...
I should have asked Nishimiya
how you really think of me...
By the way, you know, I---
Sho-chan,
Sis made pancakes for you.
Maria will go out to see the fireworks!
SL: Friends.
It's cold..
and warm..
Hi, ma'am.
Hi, Yuzuru-chan...
I finally saw you.
No one answered when I called the salon,
and entering the room was prohibited...
Oh, that is ok now.
He changed rooms today.
Let's go to the room together and see him.
Ma'am, well Shoko...
Ishida-san.
Nishimiya-san..
Nishimiya-san..I'm sorry.
Sorry again for troubling you like this.
I am very sorry.
Oh, please stop it.
My son must have done
something wrong to Shoko-san.
Ma'am.
Ishida saved my stupid sister.
I am responsible for her upbringing.
I'm sorry.
Please.
Please raise your heads.
It is important that
Shoko-san is ok.  Isn't it?
So do you, Yuzuru-chan.
Please..
Why in the world does
Ishida have to be injured!
Don't pretend to be the tragic heroine!
Say something!
"I made a lot of trouble
and bothered everyone, "
"so I'll apologize by killing myself."
"I am very sorry." ??
How arrogant you are!
Hey, Nishimiya.
You are a total blight!
Like you, a person who think everything
within your brains,
is most annoying!
Ouch!
Who are you!
Oh, you must be Nishimiya's mother...
If you cannot bring up your child,
you shouldn't have had her in the first place!
What are you doing?!
Stop it.
Stop it!
Why?
What are you doing!?
...Are you Shoko-san?
zorry.
I...I'b zorry.
I'b zorry.
I'b zorry!
I'b zorry!!
What are you doing?
I thought seeing these photos
would change sis's mind about wanting to die...
What should I have done?
Crap, it can't be opened.
She's holding it shut!
Oh, Nishimiya-san?
How about going to the lobby?
I'll buy you a drink.
(Hospital rooms #400-417)
I heard things between you
and Ya-sho in the past.
"I destroyed what Ishida-kun
created working so hard."
Do you mean what
happened at the bridge?
Actually, Ya-sho accepted
a trivial guy like me.
I learned what real friends
are at that moment,
for the first time.
Ya-sho is my "big friend",
so I am totally at a loss
until he wakes up again.
"I want to fix what I destroyed."
Oh...
It's silly you tried to kill yourself.
Even you were hurt!
You are speaking too loud, Kawai-san...
Nishimiya-san can't hear
unless we speak loudly!
Everyone is worried about you.
Everybody has had
hard experiences in life.
Everyone has, don't you think so?
So,
we have to move forward, loving ourselves,
as a whole including weaknesses.
I am relieved to know you are ok now.
Then,
you are going around to get the
members to meet at the bridge.
You are strong...
Honestly, I'm scared.
Even after Ishida-kun wakes up,
I don't have the courage to see him again.
I couldn't change myself.
I ran away again and
failed to save you again.
I'm still a coward.
Yu bill jange brom now on,
Zaara-zan...
Thank you for coming to meet me, Sho-chan.
Hey, stop it!
Nishimiya.
I found you.
Are you doing well?
Somewhat
Strange, isn't it?
I am
thinking I am going to die.
Oh.
Tuesday is almost over.
Goodbye,
Nishimiya.
No! Nishimiya!
What's this?
Hey mom!
This..
Get rid of this!
Nishimiya!
Yo!
Ha.
Pff!
Aha ha ha.
Well..
Are you all right?
Yes.
I'm glad to know
you are ok.
Nishimiya.
I'm ok now too
...more or less.
Please don't make such a serious face.
And, let me say..
Nishimiya-san.
I am sorry.
I never really apologized for
what I did to you in the past.
In addition, for what I did
after we met again.
So many things I did.
Perhaps,
I interpret you
to suit my interest.
Actually, I want to
talk more
with you.
Perhaps that's all.
But my selfish behavior had hurt you,
and forced you to choose the worst choice
Noooo, Zat'z nod gorregd.
Begauze I had nod jenged,
ju falld.
I ab
dodally blamed.
Everizing would go vell
Ib I vend away..
I'b zorry..
Don't cry, Nishimiya.
Well, Nishimiya.
Just before,
I talked to you in my dreams.
In the dream,
Perhaps I had tried to give
up many things in my life.
But I realized that is not correct.
I thought the same way as you.
But,
I realized,
that it still wasn't worth dying.
I want to apologize to others, too.
So, Nishimiya.
I want
you to
help me
live.
Nishimiya.
SL: "Friends"
Wow!
What a creepy things I just did!
Oops!
Sorry, but forget it all, Nishimiya!
Forget what I did now!
SL: It's promise.
Hey, customer!  You arrived!
Hey, Maria, are you watering flowers?
You are great!
You die?  die? dieeeeeee?
Maria, Sho-chan bring back to life.
I'm not dead, Maria.
Huh?
Is that Ueno-san?
She took care of you
when you were asleep.
Say thank you to her.
I heard you took care of me.
I'm really a no good one...
I still, or even more,
unable to like Nishimiya-san.
Huh, maybe its not ok
to force changing myself...
And, It was Shimada and Hirose,
who saved you when
you fell into the river.
They asked me not to tell it to you,
but I wanted to tell you.
Ishida.
Welcome back!
Then I'll go home.
Thank you.
Oh, it's too short, isn't it!?
No, no, you will be the
cutest with short hair!
Hi, welcome back, Sho-chan.
Huh, h...hello.
Hi, welcome to the salon...
Ishida-kun.
I'm sorry for what happened.
No, I'm sorry too.
That's right.  My son is immortal.
Hi mom, I'll go to pick Maria up.
What!?  Who is that guy?
My daughter's husband.
He returned from Brazil.
And Sho-chan.  Yuzu-chan is in your room.
Take some desserts from
the refrigerator to her.
Hey.
Hi.
Is that the winter-season
uniform?  That fits you.
By the way, take a look at this.
Oh, my. Great!
And. take another look at this.
Oh, my...
Have mercy, kind sir!
You must help me!
Sure.  Of course I will.
You have resumed going
to school, haven't you?
Yes.  Shoko gave me a
good reason to go back.
Well, I will do my best.
I wanna meet her expectations.
By the way, a school festival
will be held tomorrow?
Yes.
Shoko Nishimiya: Hello
Everyone said they are going
to the school festival tomorrow.
I will meet you at the front
gate at 10:00, it that ok?
Good morning, everyone!
Are you all ok?
I'm sorry for what I said at the bridge!
It's time to go!
I'm going to school!
Bye!  Cheer up!
Oh!
These items are used like that!
What?
Nothing.  I'll go.
Good luck!
Good morning.
SL: Good morning.
Why don't we get going?
Hey, isn't that Ishida?
Who?
Huh?  The jumping-into guy?
Oops..
SL: What's wrong with you?
Honestly, this is the
first time I told you,
I don't really fit in at school.
SL: Why?
I have difficulty looking
at everyone in the eyes.
So it is easier for
me to look downward.
Huh?  It's ok to look downward?
Ni..Nishimiya..
I can walk normally by myself you know.
Thank you, Nishimiya.
This is my class.
Ishida-kun?  Hey, it's Ishida-kun!
Are you ok now?
Nishimiya.
I feel I have a stomachache.
Sorry.
Ya-sho!
Huh?
Ya-sho?
Nagatsuka---kun?
Ya-sho, are you suffering
from a stomachache?
Ya-sho.
Hi, Nagatsuka-kun.
Good morning.  Are you ok?
Ya-sho.
Why you are looking downward?
Oh, really?  I don't know why.
Actually I came here to raise
my face to meet you all.
But I might be a bit scared...
Hey, Ya-sho..?
Ishida-kun!!
I'm really really happy you came back.
If you... oops,
If you didn't wake up,
I would have lost everything.
Ya-sho,
Don't mind any more about
what happened at the bridge.
Such minor troubles will happen
again and again as long as we live.
So, Ya-sho, please, please,
never be far from me!
Pleeeease!
Nagatsuka-kun.
I'm very sorry
for so many things.
And,
thank you.
Ya-sho!
By the way, what's happened to your mustache?
This was a praying icon for your recovery.
Nagatsuka-kun.
Huh?
Why is everyone here..
We heard Nagatsuka-kun's calling Ishida-kun's name.
I see.
Kawai-san. You have the
you-know-what to give him,
don't you?
Huh...yes, I have.
but it was a failure,
so we cannot give him that...
Why not?  Let's give it to him.
Ok...
This is.. "thousand paper cranes"
I really worked hard to collect a thousand,
but I couldn't! It is far less than a thousand...
I asked all the classmates
again and again, but..
I'm very sorry.
N--No, it's amazing!
It's enough.
I've never gotten anything like this before,
and I am really happy.
Thank you Kawai-san.
And, I am sorry.
I'm sorry too, Mashiba-kun.
Not at all.  You are amazing.
Ugh
You are becoming friends,
that makes me sick!
You are always so nasty
saying such things, Nao-chan!
Oh? Kawai-tchi?
Time to fight?
Hey, stop it, both of two!
Oh...Ishida-kun.
I'm sorry, Ishida-kun.
You have been through so much,
while I have not changed a bit.
Don't say so.
I have not changed, too.
Hey, let's not talk about anything
negative or serious now!.
SL: I'm sorry.
You said sorry again!
But, I suppose that is your personality.
Stu--pit! (Ha / ka)
Stu--pid. (Ba / ka)
Stupid! (Baka!)
Ah..
Pff!
Hey, I'm now hungry.
I'm going out to have fried chicken!
Oh, she ran away.
No, she got embarrassed.
Hi, everyone,
I have a favor to ask you all.
Is it ok?
I want to go around the
school festival together.
Hummm, it tastes really good!
Let's go to the gymnasium next!
I'm amazed he can even
show his face at school.
Hey, hey, the stall by
class #B is really good!
Really? Let's go together!
"Fell in love as"
Ah...I fell in love...
Well, please raise your face
Then you can see I am here in front of you
So stop crying any more
You gave me special time even
when my heart had been broken
A red which was a bit tangled
A white which was a color
of corridor at that days
Beginning, last time, and now
I'll convey you carving on
petals which are fluttering
Darling
I and you reflected on raindrops
No one in the world knows
Ah...I fell in love...
I don't remember since when
How many times I cried
If I count it, it will take whole night
I'll be puzzled...
Darling
What I want to convey to you now
has been same and not changed
since the past times.
Darling
The only one signpost
we can walk without losing way